Michael J. Drake Papers 1972-2008 (bulk 1973-1986)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series V: Scholarship files 1972-2005.
  - Subseries 2: Articles, circa 1960-2005
    - A Unified approach to a problem: Petrological and geochemical studies of lithic fragments from Apollo 15 soils, circa 1973(2) (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Descartes mountains and Caley plains compositions and provenance, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - The Oxidation state of europium as an indicator of oxygen fugacity, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Evolution of major mineral compositions and trace element abundances during fractional crystallization of a model lunar composition, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Plagioclase – melt equilibria, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Equivalence of equations describing trace element distribution during equilibrium partial melting, circa 1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Composition and evolution of the eucrite parent body: evidence from rare earth elements, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Quantitative micro autoradiography by x-ray emission micro-analysis, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Petrology and geochemistry of lithic fragments separated from the Apollo 15 deep drill core, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Depth of lunar magma ocean, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Quench temperatures of Moore County and other eucrites: Residence time on eucrites parent body, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - “Henry’s Law” behavior of Sm in a natural plagioclase/melt system: Importance of experience procedure, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - The Meteorite-asteroid connection: The Infrared spectra of eucrites, shergotties, and vesta, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Partitioning Ni between Olivine and Silicate Melt: The “Henry’s Law Problem” Reexamined, 1980 (1) (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Partitioning Ni between Olivine and Silicate Melt: The “Henry’s Law Problem” Reexamined, 1980 (2) (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Experimental investigations of trace element fractionation in Iron Meteorites,I and II, 1978-1982 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Evolution of earth and life, circa 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Petrogenesis on the Basaltic Achondrite Parent Body as inferred from modeling Cumulate Eucrite and Diogenite Formation, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Lunar Meteorite, ALHA 81005, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Origin of lunar terrae meteorite ALHA 81005: Clues from the presence of a very low titanium mare basalt clast, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Origins of the Moon, 1984; 1983 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Geochemical constraints on the Origin of the Moon, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Geochemical Constraints on Formation of the Earth, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - The Case for Planetary Sample Return Missions: Origin of the Solar System, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Core formation in the Earth and Shergottite Parent Body (SPB): Chemical Evidence from Basalts, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Constraints on the Origin of the Moon (authors reply and critical comment, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Core formation and Earth's late Accretionary History (Drake and Jones reply to Morgan,), 1986 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Experimental investigations of trace element fractionation in Iron Meteorites, III: Elemental partitioning in the system FE-NI-S-P, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Crystal/melt partitioning of Ga, Ge, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Partitioning of rare earth elements between Hibonite and melt and implications for nebular condensation of the rare earth elements, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Origin of the earth's moon constraints from alkali volatile trace elements, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - The Light Elements in the Earth's Core, circa 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - V, Cr, Mn in the earth moon, EPB and SPB and the origin of the moon: Experimental studies, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Geochemical constraints on early thermal history of the Earth, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Solubility and partitioning of Ar in Anorthite, Diopside, Forsterite, Spinel ,and Synthetic Basaltic liquids, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Oxygen isotopes and the accretion of the terrestrial planets(unpublished,), 1991 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Rb and Cs in the earth and moon, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Metal silicate thermochemistry at high temperature, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Noble gas evidence of an aqueous reservoir near the surface of Mars more recently than 1.3, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - MG-perovskite/silicate melt and garnet/silicate melt partition coefficients in the system Ca0-Mg)-Si02 at high temperatures and pressures, circa 1993 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Experiments on Ru Rh, and Pd compatibility in Fe – oxides crystallizing from Silicate melt, circa 1993 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Europium anomaly in plagioclase feldspar: Experimental results and semi-quantitative model, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - High –pressure and high-temperature experiments on core-mantle segregation in the accreting earth, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Element partitioning between mg-perovskite magnesiowustite and silicate melt at conditions of the earth’s mantle, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Fractional Martian atmosphere in the naklites, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Ion microprobe study of plagioclase-basalt partition experiments at natural concentration levels of trace elements, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Uranium in the lunar crust: Implications for lunar origin and evolution, 1996-1998 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Siderophile geochemistry of Ga, Ge, and Sn: Cationic states in silicate melts and the effect of composition in iron-nickel alloys, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - What’s is the earth made of?, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - : Experimental study of solubility and partitioning behavior of platinum up to 14 GPa and 1950 C: Implications for accretion and core formation in the earth, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Vanadium, Cr, Si, and the Mg/Si and the Mg/Si ratio in the earth and mars, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Origin of water in the terrestrial planets, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Partition of Sr, Ba, Ca, Y, Eu 2+, Eu 3+, and other REE between plagioclase feldspar and magmatic liquid: An Experimental study, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Magma Ocean by Partial Melting, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 3: Book Chapters, 1983-1989
    - The Nature and evolution of Vesta, (Asteroids and planets x book), 1979 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Lunar Petrology and Geochemistry (book unknown), 1983 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - The Moon (book chapter number 9 in Natural Satellites,)presented at the International Astronomy Union, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - The Moon (book chapter number eight in Solid Earth and Planets, no date (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Series VI: Subject files
  This series consists of material relating to Michael J. Drake's professional interests and research, the series is arranged alphabetically.
  - ALHS 81005, 9 lunar meteorite notes and figures, circa 1983 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Allende meteorite, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Amphibole /liquid (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Apollo core catalog, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Apollo deep drill core catalog – MS, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Apollo 15 deep drill core, 15003, 545, October 1987 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - A15 Deep drill core teletype output, circa 1975 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Apollo 16 lunar samples, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Burline Project, circa 2001 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Cameca Microprobe, 1987- August 1989 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Cameca Microprobe, October 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Crustal Genesis Program – Arizona Research Lab (ARL), 1982- June 1983 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Crustal Genesis Program – Arizona Research Lab (ARL), 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Department of Planetary Sciences and Lunar Planetary Lab Annual Reports, 1975-1981 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Department of Planetary Sciences and Lunar Planetary Lab Faculty meetings, 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Department of Planetary Sciences and lunar Planetary Lab -selection of new director/head, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Eu 2+/Eu 3+ (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Early Crustal Steering Committee, 1980-1983 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Eucrites (meteorite), circa 1970’s (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Electron Microprobe-New, 2007-2008 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Experimental Partitioning of Ga and Ge in Fo-Di-An (Glossy prints,), undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Fe Solid/Fe Liquid, [1978] (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Fe-FeS Partitioning, [1980] (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Fractional partial melting, circa 1976 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Garnet, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Geochemical structure of the crust, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Geologic maps Oregon, Scotland, Great Britain, circa 1957 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - H1 and H2 cumulates-partial melting, circa 1976 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Henry's Law, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Hibonite/Melt Dsm, [1980] (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Horizon, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - JOEL Electronic Micro probe, 1987-1989 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Lunar modeling programs, October 1976 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Lunar Meteorites MAC 88104 and 88105, [1983, 1989-1990] (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Lunar Origin Group Discussions, October 1984 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Lunar Origin Group T-Loc, [1983-1984] (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Lunar Origin Group T-Loc, September 1985 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Lunar Planetary Laboratory budget, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Lunar Planetary Laboratory/Science Building Renovations, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Lunar sample forms, 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Magnetic Iron Meteorites/Goldstein correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Mare basalts calculations with redundant D’s, circa 1975 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Mare basalt, fractional, circa 1976 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Mare Basalts: Source Regions and Assimilation Program, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Mars Colloquium, September 1981 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Mars Program, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Mars Weathering, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Meteorite Sightings - Tucson, July 16, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Murthy’s Science Reply “High Temperatures”, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - NASA Budget, 1981-1983 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Noble Gas - C. Leigh Broadhurst, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - SNC: Noble Metals, no date (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Photographs Miscellaneous, [1982] (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Public Broadcasting Program, What About Modeling In Science, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Radioactive Materials, 1977-1983 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Radiation Safety and levels in the Science Building, July 31, 1978-January 15, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Radiation Safety and levels in the Science Building, January 11, 1979-October 14, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Rare Gas Partitioning, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Research Notes, [1983-1984] (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - SAO-UO A17 samples, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Senate Appropriations Committee-NASA Lunar Analysis, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Stony-Irons Meteorites, [1976] (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Processing Polymict eucrite meteorites ALHA81011 and ALHA8010, circa 1983] (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Apollo 15 deep drill core color prints, circa 1980’s (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Asteroid 15003 photographs, circa 1980’s (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Lunar meteorite ALHA 81005, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Series VII: Instructional files:
  Classes taught by Dr. Drake, arranged chronology,
  - Geochemical evolution of the terrestrial planet, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Geosciences 258 lectures, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Ply. Sc. 321, circa 1978 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Planetary sciences 244a, circa 1979 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - PtyS 568 constitution of the terrestrial planets, circa 1980 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - PtyS 571 origin of the the moon, fall 1985 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - PtyS 520 meteorites, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - PtyS 579a advanced igneous petrology, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - PtyS 510 physical chemistry and nuclear chemistry, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Series VIII: College class work:
  - Physics 101, , circa 1965 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous class notes, circa 1965 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Geochemistry 307, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - German, circa, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Math 441, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Geology 513, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Seminar in Cosmo-chemistry, circa 1968 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Math with statistics, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Chemistry 411 and 412, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Chemistry 453 statistical mechanics, circa 1969 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Advanced Fortran IV, CS 407, circa 1969 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Advanced Geochemistry, circa 1970 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Geology 562, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Classification of Igneous rocks, GY303, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Solutions in mathematics library, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Mathematics 101, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - GY 201 and 202, circa 1966 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - GY 203 and 204, circa 1965 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Series IX: Scientific Notebooks
  Arranged chronologically, 1968-1993
  - Experimental runs, lab book 1, circa 1968 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Probe work on experiments (notes) no. 1, 1969-1971 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Natural Rocks, 1970-1974 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Probe work no.2, 1971-1974 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Synthetic runs, 1971-1978 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - A15 deep drill core – 15003, Luna 24, Allende, 1974-1977 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Probe book no. 3, Garnet/Liquid, Amphibole/Liquid, Diopside/Liquid, 1974-1978 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Richard Bild, September 30, 1977-Feburary 15, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Probe book, no.4, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Synthetic runs v.4, June 12,1978 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Synthetic runs v.5, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Probe book (Drake/Stephens), 1978-1980 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Probe book (Drake/Lo Faro), 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Rb/Sr (Lo Faro/Drake), 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Rb/Sr (Lo Faro/Drake), 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Furnace book (Drake/Stephens), 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - No title, 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - No title, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Glass Lab, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Hibonite experiment (Stephens/Drake), 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Microprobe notebook, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - No title, circa 1982-1996 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - C.L. Broadhurst, 1984-1989 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Run log, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Diamond Anvil Experiments, 1991-1993 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Probe, undated (Box 13, Folder 26)
- Series IX: Photographic Negatives, Circa,1977-1980
  Eleven negative rolls and approximately forty seven negative flat strips, some of the negatives are labeled and dated but there are a few with no information.